<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-06-23T19:24:45+00:00</updated><id>https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Learning-Jun-13</title><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jun-13/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning-Jun-13"/><published>2025-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jun-13</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jun-13/"><![CDATA[<ul> <li>Sass business, then and now. In the past, software business is more geared towards one time fee (i.e $500 for a microsoft office), now however, most software is on a subscription model, which is much more sustainable as well as stable revenue (i.e Google Docs). LTV of each software is 1 / Churn rate, Customer Acquistion Cost is the cost in order to spent on each customer (i.e marketing, benefits, cost of capital), if a Sass business have this ratio is less than 1, then it’s a bad business. Good companies like Amazon or Spotify will have a huge LTV and CAC. <ul> <li>Net New MRR: the incremental dollars add to install base each month. Basically how much the business is growing. These incremental dollar formula is something similar to: New MRR (New Customers) + Upgrade MRR (Existing Customers) - Downgrade MRR (Existing Customer downgrade product) - Cancellation MRR (Lost Custoemrs). This need to be continualy positive for the company to grow. However, MRR is an internal tool and it’s not a really public number.</li> </ul> </li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sass business, then and now. In the past, software business is more geared towards one time fee (i.e $500 for a microsoft office), now however, most software is on a subscription model, which is much more sustainable as well as stable revenue (i.e Google Docs). LTV of each software is 1 / Churn rate, Customer Acquistion Cost is the cost in order to spent on each customer (i.e marketing, benefits, cost of capital), if a Sass business have this ratio is less than 1, then it’s a bad business. Good companies like Amazon or Spotify will have a huge LTV and CAC. Net New MRR: the incremental dollars add to install base each month. Basically how much the business is growing. These incremental dollar formula is something similar to: New MRR (New Customers) + Upgrade MRR (Existing Customers) - Downgrade MRR (Existing Customer downgrade product) - Cancellation MRR (Lost Custoemrs). This need to be continualy positive for the company to grow. However, MRR is an internal tool and it’s not a really public number.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Learning-Jun-12</title><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jun-12/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning-Jun-12"/><published>2025-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jun-12</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jun-12/"><![CDATA[<ul> <li>My STB position balloon to 20% return now but with only half of my capital, anyway it’s a special situation stock and it’s not my idea so it’s kinda hard to know when to buy and when to exit, but I can kinda understand the stock where we just need a dividend yield to kick in and it will balloon in value.</li> <li>AAM drops yesterday which gives me a place to buy into it, I will again consider it a little bit more before buying</li> <li>One of the stock I once aimed at is HSL whose just rise over nearly 30% in a few days, this is also a Graham kind of stock and it behaves similar to FCM. I wonder if I did any computation on it in the past. Not much but it’s also a Graham type of play</li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My STB position balloon to 20% return now but with only half of my capital, anyway it’s a special situation stock and it’s not my idea so it’s kinda hard to know when to buy and when to exit, but I can kinda understand the stock where we just need a dividend yield to kick in and it will balloon in value. AAM drops yesterday which gives me a place to buy into it, I will again consider it a little bit more before buying One of the stock I once aimed at is HSL whose just rise over nearly 30% in a few days, this is also a Graham kind of stock and it behaves similar to FCM. I wonder if I did any computation on it in the past. Not much but it’s also a Graham type of play]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Learnings-Jun-10</title><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learnings-jun-10/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learnings-Jun-10"/><published>2025-06-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learnings-jun-10</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learnings-jun-10/"><![CDATA[<ul> <li>Contrary to my estimation, STB is still rising strong despite the tariff uncertainty, I already liquidate half of my position so there is no good reentry point, but again, conservative is better and it’s still a month before everything plays out on July 9th</li> <li>I will look at VTO more in depth today and try to understand its business and is there any room for growth or any value can be achieved from it. <ul> <li>So the big thesis is that this company is sitting on a huge 900 bil cash pile. There are other lots of strong business sign, corporate buyback, never missed a dividends, as well as a strong free cash flow history, always postive and healthy at around 200 bil for the past 7 years. But the key value is this cash pile, cash often does not mean anything for growth, but its a good estimation of the company current value. From what I read it seems that this cash will be used to buy a new ship without using any debt, which in turn means that revenue will likely grow and contribute to the dividend yield (if the stock price stay the same). Again as a value investor, I’m looking to compound more than the market, at 9% a year for 3 years, that is likely better in the short term than the overall market. So with this value of 9% the stock most likely will be traded at around 16,000 for the next year, not a huge, huge compounding but I guess it’s the best I could find right now and I should just invest when the opportunity arise.</li> </ul> </li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Contrary to my estimation, STB is still rising strong despite the tariff uncertainty, I already liquidate half of my position so there is no good reentry point, but again, conservative is better and it’s still a month before everything plays out on July 9th I will look at VTO more in depth today and try to understand its business and is there any room for growth or any value can be achieved from it. So the big thesis is that this company is sitting on a huge 900 bil cash pile. There are other lots of strong business sign, corporate buyback, never missed a dividends, as well as a strong free cash flow history, always postive and healthy at around 200 bil for the past 7 years. But the key value is this cash pile, cash often does not mean anything for growth, but its a good estimation of the company current value. From what I read it seems that this cash will be used to buy a new ship without using any debt, which in turn means that revenue will likely grow and contribute to the dividend yield (if the stock price stay the same). Again as a value investor, I’m looking to compound more than the market, at 9% a year for 3 years, that is likely better in the short term than the overall market. So with this value of 9% the stock most likely will be traded at around 16,000 for the next year, not a huge, huge compounding but I guess it’s the best I could find right now and I should just invest when the opportunity arise.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Learning-Jun-9</title><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jun-9/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning-Jun-9"/><published>2025-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jun-9</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jun-9/"><![CDATA[<ul> <li>Market lost 20 points which is expected but still no opportunity arises from it. I’m still trying to look through some predictable and cheap business that I can invest in as a value play but still not that fruitful. Some stocks I’ve looked through: <ul> <li>VTO, extremely cash rich, however it operate in the oil transportation business which is extremely unpredictable and cyclical. With uncertainties in the market, buying in right now will often not yield any good result. When I say cash rich, it means extremely cash rich, 900 bil in cash with 990 bil valuation and little capex in the past 2 years. Debt payment has been steady. I think I can look at this further in the coming days to come up with a thesis</li> <li>VPG, stock drops 5 days in a row due to arrest of its CEO and chairman. Very cash rich, sitting on 1600 bil while valued at 700 bil. However, very debt heavy, over 4000 bil in short term debt and no past debt repayment, so if I’m not mistaken, this should be a case of debt restructuring if I want to unlock a profit</li> <li>HAH, this stock manage to return over 1500% in 5 years, and this is a classic Peter Lynch play where a business is growing at 30 - 40% CAGR, extremely rare. This only helps if you know the business and know that it can expand successfully, which I would have no way of knowing, especially if the business of port and transport. I guess it’s because the boom in logistic during 2020 - 2022 period and this company caught the tailwind of it, looking through the numbers, it’s because the company managed to boost its earnings. Moreover, it recently surges because business try to import as much as possible during the tariff pause, which generate a lot of money for the business. So that’s a small catalyst, not a value play.</li> </ul> </li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="investing"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Market lost 20 points which is expected but still no opportunity arises from it. I’m still trying to look through some predictable and cheap business that I can invest in as a value play but still not that fruitful. Some stocks I’ve looked through: VTO, extremely cash rich, however it operate in the oil transportation business which is extremely unpredictable and cyclical. With uncertainties in the market, buying in right now will often not yield any good result. When I say cash rich, it means extremely cash rich, 900 bil in cash with 990 bil valuation and little capex in the past 2 years. Debt payment has been steady. I think I can look at this further in the coming days to come up with a thesis VPG, stock drops 5 days in a row due to arrest of its CEO and chairman. Very cash rich, sitting on 1600 bil while valued at 700 bil. However, very debt heavy, over 4000 bil in short term debt and no past debt repayment, so if I’m not mistaken, this should be a case of debt restructuring if I want to unlock a profit HAH, this stock manage to return over 1500% in 5 years, and this is a classic Peter Lynch play where a business is growing at 30 - 40% CAGR, extremely rare. This only helps if you know the business and know that it can expand successfully, which I would have no way of knowing, especially if the business of port and transport. I guess it’s because the boom in logistic during 2020 - 2022 period and this company caught the tailwind of it, looking through the numbers, it’s because the company managed to boost its earnings. Moreover, it recently surges because business try to import as much as possible during the tariff pause, which generate a lot of money for the business. So that’s a small catalyst, not a value play.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Learning-Jun-6</title><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jun-6/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning-Jun-6"/><published>2025-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jun-6</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jun-6/"><![CDATA[<ul> <li>I will look through some of the best performing stock in the past 10 years to see what’s the business pattern. But again, is this even the right way to do it? I’m buying on margin of safety, not looking for growth or the best perofrming business because you need a lot of things go right to achieve that growth. I’m strictly using a value play, meaning a distressed company, not a business that grow exponetially. Well, I can look through the numbers and see but not look at the growth driving things. <ul> <li>Unfortunately, this is not an organic growing business with cash flows and reinvest and the low capital expenditure and all that. Firstly they 10x their revenue just because they combine revenue with another company (and the government allow it), and then the price of their product rise which is not a value investment type, so I will not invest in this company even though it’s best performing in the last 10 years.</li> </ul> </li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I will look through some of the best performing stock in the past 10 years to see what’s the business pattern. But again, is this even the right way to do it? I’m buying on margin of safety, not looking for growth or the best perofrming business because you need a lot of things go right to achieve that growth. I’m strictly using a value play, meaning a distressed company, not a business that grow exponetially. Well, I can look through the numbers and see but not look at the growth driving things. Unfortunately, this is not an organic growing business with cash flows and reinvest and the low capital expenditure and all that. Firstly they 10x their revenue just because they combine revenue with another company (and the government allow it), and then the price of their product rise which is not a value investment type, so I will not invest in this company even though it’s best performing in the last 10 years.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Learnings 6-5-2025</title><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learnings-6-5-2025/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learnings 6-5-2025"/><published>2025-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learnings-6-5-2025</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learnings-6-5-2025/"><![CDATA[<ul> <li>Read some books today including Merger Masters and Art of Investing, nothing new that very new that I learn just reiterate <ul> <li>Merger Masters is just biography of people who did merging, and the only thing I found might be useful is the checklist for analyzing a merger</li> <li>Art of value investing have a wide quote from value investors, and it’s true that everyone have different and opposing way of thinking but at least I can see some patterns (which I’ve known like analyze companies that’s low coverage (FIT and FCM exemplifies this) and try to invest in busines that’s easy to understand and predict).</li> <li>However, the Art of value investing book have the idea generation chapter which looks interesting, insider buying is repeated a lot, and some other advanced metrics that I’m yet to understand like return of capital, specific cash flow characteristics, and so on. And of course, computer screens and metrics, another interesting they say is too look for sudden change in margins or just developments situation within the company</li> <li>Dhando Investor which have a lot of good ideas, one standout thing to me is the Kelly’s formula of how to decide what amount to rllocate based on each investment using probability and odds, this is from a book and I guess it’s not that popular yet. So the formula is % of bankroll = (bp - q) / b where b is the net odds (i.e bet 1 get 3 then b = 3) p probability of win, q probability of lose. So if you get $2 80% of the time in the investment from $1, using the formula, you should bet 60% of your bankroll</li> </ul> </li> <li>It’s been a long time since I write but a lot of developments within how I think in the past month <ul> <li>Firstly, tariffs, market has been going strong but it seems that the tariffs hit is looming and there’s no positive negotiation in the US side. When I think about it (or my dad told me), this is a Soros advice situation where when things are uncertain, think about how much you would lose if you’re right and how much you gain if you’re wrong. With the current valuation, it will be a 20% loss if I’m wrong, and around 7% gain if I’m right.</li> <li>Then, I’m seriously worried about my Graham type of investment. Well, I mean because it’s not doing well and companies like Vingroup, NVL, VIX still beat and drive the market upwards. I’m debating on whether focus on these special money making situation, like the VIC receiving money interest-free of $67 bil, or the previous BPM investment that bet on the growth and expanding margin would pay more dividends and grow the dividend yield, and many other things. This is still open for debate and I may need to survey all of the historical performances of the stock to think more about the market. I just need the average long term compounder, not the 10 times my money.</li> </ul> </li> <li>Scanned through a bit of the highest return over 5 year and 10 year period of companies in Vietnam, will look through some of these companies and how did it do it.</li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="investing"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Read some books today including Merger Masters and Art of Investing, nothing new that very new that I learn just reiterate Merger Masters is just biography of people who did merging, and the only thing I found might be useful is the checklist for analyzing a merger Art of value investing have a wide quote from value investors, and it’s true that everyone have different and opposing way of thinking but at least I can see some patterns (which I’ve known like analyze companies that’s low coverage (FIT and FCM exemplifies this) and try to invest in busines that’s easy to understand and predict). However, the Art of value investing book have the idea generation chapter which looks interesting, insider buying is repeated a lot, and some other advanced metrics that I’m yet to understand like return of capital, specific cash flow characteristics, and so on. And of course, computer screens and metrics, another interesting they say is too look for sudden change in margins or just developments situation within the company Dhando Investor which have a lot of good ideas, one standout thing to me is the Kelly’s formula of how to decide what amount to rllocate based on each investment using probability and odds, this is from a book and I guess it’s not that popular yet. So the formula is % of bankroll=(bp - q) / b where b is the net odds (i.e bet 1 get 3 then b=3) p probability of win, q probability of lose. So if you get $2 80% of the time in the investment from $1, using the formula, you should bet 60% of your bankroll It’s been a long time since I write but a lot of developments within how I think in the past month Firstly, tariffs, market has been going strong but it seems that the tariffs hit is looming and there’s no positive negotiation in the US side. When I think about it (or my dad told me), this is a Soros advice situation where when things are uncertain, think about how much you would lose if you’re right and how much you gain if you’re wrong. With the current valuation, it will be a 20% loss if I’m wrong, and around 7% gain if I’m right. Then, I’m seriously worried about my Graham type of investment. Well, I mean because it’s not doing well and companies like Vingroup, NVL, VIX still beat and drive the market upwards. I’m debating on whether focus on these special money making situation, like the VIC receiving money interest-free of $67 bil, or the previous BPM investment that bet on the growth and expanding margin would pay more dividends and grow the dividend yield, and many other things. This is still open for debate and I may need to survey all of the historical performances of the stock to think more about the market. I just need the average long term compounder, not the 10 times my money. Scanned through a bit of the highest return over 5 year and 10 year period of companies in Vietnam, will look through some of these companies and how did it do it.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New post</title><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/new-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New post"/><published>2025-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/new-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/new-post/"><![CDATA[<p>Start writing here. I don’t know what to do yet, but fuck yeah</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Start writing here. I don’t know what to do yet, but fuck yeah]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">a post with plotly.js</title><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/plotly/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="a post with plotly.js"/><published>2025-03-26T14:24:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-26T14:24:00+00:00</updated><id>https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/plotly</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/plotly/"><![CDATA[<p>This is an example post with some <a href="https://plotly.com/javascript/">plotly</a> code.</p> <div class="language-markdown highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="p">```</span><span class="nl">plotly
</span><span class="sb">{
  "data": [
    {
      "x": [1, 2, 3, 4],
      "y": [10, 15, 13, 17],
      "type": "scatter"
    },
    {
      "x": [1, 2, 3, 4],
      "y": [16, 5, 11, 9],
      "type": "scatter"
    }
  ]
}</span>
<span class="p">```</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <p>Which generates:</p> <pre><code class="language-plotly">{
  "data": [
    {
      "x": [1, 2, 3, 4],
      "y": [10, 15, 13, 17],
      "type": "scatter"
    },
    {
      "x": [1, 2, 3, 4],
      "y": [16, 5, 11, 9],
      "type": "scatter"
    }
  ]
}
</code></pre> <p>Also another example chart.</p> <div class="language-markdown highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="p">```</span><span class="nl">plotly
</span><span class="sb">{
  "data": [
    {
      "x": [1, 2, 3, 4],
      "y": [10, 15, 13, 17],
      "mode": "markers"
    },
    {
      "x": [2, 3, 4, 5],
      "y": [16, 5, 11, 9],
      "mode": "lines"
    },
    {
      "x": [1, 2, 3, 4],
      "y": [12, 9, 15, 12],
      "mode": "lines+markers"
    }
  ],
  "layout": {
    "title": {
      "text": "Line and Scatter Plot"
    }
  }
}</span>
<span class="p">```</span>
</code></pre></div></div> <p>This is how it looks like:</p> <pre><code class="language-plotly">{
  "data": [
    {
      "x": [1, 2, 3, 4],
      "y": [10, 15, 13, 17],
      "mode": "markers"
    },
    {
      "x": [2, 3, 4, 5],
      "y": [16, 5, 11, 9],
      "mode": "lines"
    },
    {
      "x": [1, 2, 3, 4],
      "y": [12, 9, 15, 12],
      "mode": "lines+markers"
    }
  ],
  "layout": {
    "title": {
      "text": "Line and Scatter Plot"
    }
  }
}
</code></pre>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="formatting"/><category term="charts"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[this is what included plotly.js code could look like]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">a post with image galleries</title><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2024/photo-gallery/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="a post with image galleries"/><published>2024-12-04T01:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-04T01:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2024/photo-gallery</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2024/photo-gallery/"><![CDATA[<p>The images in this post are all zoomable, arranged into different mini-galleries using different libraries.</p> <h2 id="lightbox2"><a href="https://lokeshdhakar.com/projects/lightbox2/">Lightbox2</a></h2> <p><a href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/1/img-2500.jpg" data-lightbox="roadtrip"><img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/1/img-200.jpg"/></a> <a href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/2/img-2500.jpg" data-lightbox="roadtrip"><img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/2/img-200.jpg"/></a> <a href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/3/img-2500.jpg" data-lightbox="roadtrip"><img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/3/img-200.jpg"/></a></p> <hr/> <h2 id="photoswipe"><a href="https://photoswipe.com/">PhotoSwipe</a></h2> <div class="pswp-gallery pswp-gallery--single-column" id="gallery--getting-started"> <a href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/2/img-2500.jpg" data-pswp-width="1669" data-pswp-height="2500" target="_blank"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/2/img-200.jpg" alt=""/> </a> <a href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/7/img-2500.jpg" data-pswp-width="1875" data-pswp-height="2500" data-cropped="true" target="_blank"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/7/img-200.jpg" alt=""/> </a> <a href="https://unsplash.com" data-pswp-src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/3/img-2500.jpg" data-pswp-width="2500" data-pswp-height="1666" target="_blank"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/3/img-200.jpg" alt=""/> </a> <div> <a href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/6/img-2500.jpg" data-pswp-width="2500" data-pswp-height="1667" target="_blank"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/6/img-200.jpg" alt=""/> </a> </div> </div> <hr/> <h2 id="spotlight-js"><a href="https://nextapps-de.github.io/spotlight/">Spotlight JS</a></h2> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/1/img-2500.jpg"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/1/img-200.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/2/img-2500.jpg"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/2/img-200.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/3/img-2500.jpg"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/3/img-200.jpg"/> </a> </div> <div class="spotlight-group"> <a class="spotlight" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/4/img-2500.jpg"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/4/img-200.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/5/img-2500.jpg"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/5/img-200.jpg"/> </a> <a class="spotlight" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/6/img-2500.jpg"> <img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/6/img-200.jpg"/> </a> </div> <hr/> <h2 id="venobox"><a href="https://veno.es/venobox/">Venobox</a></h2> <p><a class="venobox" data-gall="myGallery" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/1/img-2500.jpg"><img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/1/img-200.jpg"/></a> <a class="venobox" data-gall="myGallery" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/2/img-2500.jpg"><img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/2/img-200.jpg"/></a> <a class="venobox" data-gall="myGallery" href="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/3/img-2500.jpg"><img src="https://cdn.photoswipe.com/photoswipe-demo-images/photos/3/img-200.jpg"/></a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="formatting"/><category term="images"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[this is what included image galleries could look like]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Google Gemini updates: Flash 1.5, Gemma 2 and Project Astra</title><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Google Gemini updates: Flash 1.5, Gemma 2 and Project Astra"/><published>2024-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra/"><![CDATA[<p>May 14, 2024[[read-time]] min read We’re introducing a series of updates across the Gemini family of models, including the new 1.5 Flash, our lightweight model for speed and efficiency, and Project Astra, our vision for the future of AI assistants. In December, we launched our first natively multimodal model Gemini 1.0 in three sizes: Ultra, Pro and Nano. Just a few months later we released 1.5 Pro, with enhanced performance and a breakthrough long context window of 1 million tokens.Developers and enterprise customers have been putting 1.5 Pro to use in incredible ways and finding its long context window, multimodal reasoning capabilities and impressive overall performance incredibly useful.We know from user feedback that some applications need lower latency and a lower cost to serve. This inspired us to keep innovating, so today, we’re introducing Gemini 1.5 Flash: a model that’s lighter-weight than 1.5 Pro, and designed to be fast and efficient to serve at scale.Both 1.5 Pro and 1.5 Flash are available in public preview with a 1 million token context window in Google AI Studio and Vertex AI. And now, 1.5 Pro is also available with a 2 million token context window via waitlist to developers using the API and to Google Cloud customers.We’re also introducing updates across the Gemini family of models, announcing our next generation of open models, Gemma 2, and sharing progress on the future of AI assistants, with Project Astra.Context lengths of leading foundation models compared with Gemini 1.5’s 2 million token capability1.5 Flash is the newest addition to the Gemini model family and the fastest Gemini model served in the API. It’s optimized for high-volume, high-frequency tasks at scale, is more cost-efficient to serve and features our breakthrough long context window.While it’s a lighter weight model than 1.5 Pro, it’s highly capable of multimodal reasoning across vast amounts of information and delivers impressive quality for its size.The new Gemini 1.5 Flash model is optimized for speed and efficiency, is highly capable of multimodal reasoning and features our breakthrough long context window.1.5 Flash excels at summarization, chat applications, image and video captioning, data extraction from long documents and tables, and more. This is because it’s been trained by 1.5 Pro through a process called “distillation,” where the most essential knowledge and skills from a larger model are transferred to a smaller, more efficient model.Read more about 1.5 Flash in our updated Gemini 1.5 technical report, on the Gemini technology page, and learn about 1.5 Flash’s availability and pricing.Over the last few months, we’ve significantly improved 1.5 Pro, our best model for general performance across a wide range of tasks.Beyond extending its context window to 2 million tokens, we’ve enhanced its code generation, logical reasoning and planning, multi-turn conversation, and audio and image understanding through data and algorithmic advances. We see strong improvements on public and internal benchmarks for each of these tasks.1.5 Pro can now follow increasingly complex and nuanced instructions, including ones that specify product-level behavior involving role, format and style. We’ve improved control over the model’s responses for specific use cases, like crafting the persona and response style of a chat agent or automating workflows through multiple function calls. And we’ve enabled users to steer model behavior by setting system instructions.We added audio understanding in the Gemini API and Google AI Studio, so 1.5 Pro can now reason across image and audio for videos uploaded in Google AI Studio. And we’re now integrating 1.5 Pro into Google products, including Gemini Advanced and in Workspace apps.Read more about 1.5 Pro in our updated Gemini 1.5 technical report and on the Gemini technology page.Gemini Nano is expanding beyond text-only inputs to include images as well. Starting with Pixel, applications using Gemini Nano with Multimodality will be able to understand the world the way people do — not just through text, but also through sight, sound and spoken language.Read more about Gemini 1.0 Nano on Android.Today, we’re also sharing a series of updates to Gemma, our family of open models built from the same research and technology used to create the Gemini models.We’re announcing Gemma 2, our next generation of open models for responsible AI innovation. Gemma 2 has a new architecture designed for breakthrough performance and efficiency, and will be available in new sizes.The Gemma family is also expanding with PaliGemma, our first vision-language model inspired by PaLI-3. And we’ve upgraded our Responsible Generative AI Toolkit with LLM Comparator for evaluating the quality of model responses.Read more on the Developer blog.As part of Google DeepMind’s mission to build AI responsibly to benefit humanity, we’ve always wanted to develop universal AI agents that can be helpful in everyday life. That’s why today, we’re sharing our progress in building the future of AI assistants with Project Astra (advanced seeing and talking responsive agent).To be truly useful, an agent needs to understand and respond to the complex and dynamic world just like people do — and take in and remember what it sees and hears to understand context and take action. It also needs to be proactive, teachable and personal, so users can talk to it naturally and without lag or delay.While we’ve made incredible progress developing AI systems that can understand multimodal information, getting response time down to something conversational is a difficult engineering challenge. Over the past few years, we’ve been working to improve how our models perceive, reason and converse to make the pace and quality of interaction feel more natural.Building on Gemini, we’ve developed prototype agents that can process information faster by continuously encoding video frames, combining the video and speech input into a timeline of events, and caching this information for efficient recall.By leveraging our leading speech models, we also enhanced how they sound, giving the agents a wider range of intonations. These agents can better understand the context they’re being used in, and respond quickly, in conversation.With technology like this, it’s easy to envision a future where people could have an expert AI assistant by their side, through a phone or glasses. And some of these capabilities are coming to Google products, like the Gemini app and web experience, later this year.We’ve made incredible progress so far with our family of Gemini models, and we’re always striving to advance the state-of-the-art even further. By investing in a relentless production line of innovation, we’re able to explore new ideas at the frontier, while also unlocking the possibility of new and exciting Gemini use cases.Learn more about Gemini and its capabilities. Your information will be used in accordance with Google’s privacy policy.</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>      Done. Just one step more.
    
      Check your inbox to confirm your subscription.
    You are already subscribed to our newsletter.
    You can also subscribe with a
    different email address
    
    .
    
  Let’s stay in touch. Get the latest news from Google in your inbox.
          Follow Us
</code></pre></div></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re sharing updates across our Gemini family of models and a glimpse of Project Astra, our vision for the future of AI assistants.]]></summary></entry></feed>