<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-07-24T23:53:21+00:00</updated><id>https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Learning Jul 22</title><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jul-22/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning Jul 22"/><published>2025-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jul-22</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jul-22/"><![CDATA[<ul> <li>The market breaks 1500 now, it’s been a long time that I care about the market but this is now essentially just reading the market technique that I learn in the past. The market average more than 1 billion dollar which is a huge money coming in so the momentum will keep going higher and higher. This year is a huge lesson where I should never sell the stock so quickly unless there is a huge valuation shift. Even with big things happen, business value will often not face the impact directly for the short period of time and my margin of safety is still impact, it’s just the return maybe affected a little bit. Also, Peter Lynch says that know what you own and why you own it, STB is a work out, and I should never sell until the entire thing work out, which is that STB will manage to return dividends to its shareholders. (A small business lesson I learn is that when you have earnings and income, most of the income will go to shareholders and business often leave out a small chunk called retained income. STB has compounded 10 years of no dividends so just when the restructuring is finished, the dividend will be huge). So just commit this to memory: Never sell until the value is realized. I think I also heard from Howard Marks today that the piece of business should never be sold so quickly because you give up future return.</li> <li>My stock is lagging behind the market a little bit. I talked to my friend the other day who is a finance student and he says that since the market is uptrend, just buy anything and you will lock in a profit. Well, I just realize that right now I can’t not gather good arguments to easily explain why you should never use that mentality to buy stocks, or the trade on news and the swing trading is not great. I mean it works, but it’s not very satisfying and it’s more luck than skill and it’s not a great engine to build wealth. But whatever, as long as they make the money so I could not really criticize them, but that’s a wealth destroyer. Similar to growth stock like Cathy Wood who place Tesla stock worth of $1500 on literally 0 basis of value. Good and bright future usually never work out. Howard Marks also today in his technology stock bubble era memo also mention how you should not buy stock on how it will shape the new world order or game changing the technology (Say Airline Companies, their business is literally 0 profit, or early Amazon and other, very little retained earnings). These are all relied on exceptionally game changing high demand that the more capital you put it, it will fill all of the new demand (which is hard to quantify and high risk, take early Nike, early Microsoft, Apple). If you manage to find it with a moderately good conviction that the demand for each new line will be growing, then great, but I think it’s quite rare to gauge the huge demand of those unless you are in the business (Peter Lynch Dunkin, runners and Nike).</li> <li>Despite the market level, I will add some more to my position, of course not fully deployed but add some more to my AAM stock.</li> <li>Also for Graham stocks, I could hold it as a batch for 25% of my portfolio like John Huber rather than having to be concentrated in those stock which is quite high risk.</li> <li>Can’t believe The Athletic is just 9 years old when the users and have 5 million subscribers. That’s higher than WSJ. Their story could have some business lesson rather than luck.</li> <li>Look through YC while I was using Instacart today, well I still have a small quite unachievable and hard dream of building a great software business, but that’s require a lot of things to go right, well I can experiment and think about it, but value investing is the right way for my personality and thinking to build wealth, then the other could be to “make a dent” on the world</li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The market breaks 1500 now, it’s been a long time that I care about the market but this is now essentially just reading the market technique that I learn in the past. The market average more than 1 billion dollar which is a huge money coming in so the momentum will keep going higher and higher. This year is a huge lesson where I should never sell the stock so quickly unless there is a huge valuation shift. Even with big things happen, business value will often not face the impact directly for the short period of time and my margin of safety is still impact, it’s just the return maybe affected a little bit. Also, Peter Lynch says that know what you own and why you own it, STB is a work out, and I should never sell until the entire thing work out, which is that STB will manage to return dividends to its shareholders. (A small business lesson I learn is that when you have earnings and income, most of the income will go to shareholders and business often leave out a small chunk called retained income. STB has compounded 10 years of no dividends so just when the restructuring is finished, the dividend will be huge). So just commit this to memory: Never sell until the value is realized. I think I also heard from Howard Marks today that the piece of business should never be sold so quickly because you give up future return. My stock is lagging behind the market a little bit. I talked to my friend the other day who is a finance student and he says that since the market is uptrend, just buy anything and you will lock in a profit. Well, I just realize that right now I can’t not gather good arguments to easily explain why you should never use that mentality to buy stocks, or the trade on news and the swing trading is not great. I mean it works, but it’s not very satisfying and it’s more luck than skill and it’s not a great engine to build wealth. But whatever, as long as they make the money so I could not really criticize them, but that’s a wealth destroyer. Similar to growth stock like Cathy Wood who place Tesla stock worth of $1500 on literally 0 basis of value. Good and bright future usually never work out. Howard Marks also today in his technology stock bubble era memo also mention how you should not buy stock on how it will shape the new world order or game changing the technology (Say Airline Companies, their business is literally 0 profit, or early Amazon and other, very little retained earnings). These are all relied on exceptionally game changing high demand that the more capital you put it, it will fill all of the new demand (which is hard to quantify and high risk, take early Nike, early Microsoft, Apple). If you manage to find it with a moderately good conviction that the demand for each new line will be growing, then great, but I think it’s quite rare to gauge the huge demand of those unless you are in the business (Peter Lynch Dunkin, runners and Nike). Despite the market level, I will add some more to my position, of course not fully deployed but add some more to my AAM stock. Also for Graham stocks, I could hold it as a batch for 25% of my portfolio like John Huber rather than having to be concentrated in those stock which is quite high risk. Can’t believe The Athletic is just 9 years old when the users and have 5 million subscribers. That’s higher than WSJ. Their story could have some business lesson rather than luck. Look through YC while I was using Instacart today, well I still have a small quite unachievable and hard dream of building a great software business, but that’s require a lot of things to go right, well I can experiment and think about it, but value investing is the right way for my personality and thinking to build wealth, then the other could be to “make a dent” on the world]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Learning Jul 16</title><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jul-16/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning Jul 16"/><published>2025-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jul-16</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jul-16/"><![CDATA[<p>I bought a premium stock data tool today, will use it and my first stock analysis in a while is once again <a href="evernote:///view/246850237/s432/8da511dd-ada4-daf5-17d9-f9f0f5900ef0#cbe4453a-1aa1-4757-82b7-d7f213de48f6/775bbfcb-d458-491f-ac8e-da9bcb6afb69">SGN</a> equipped with my new valuation knowledge. So even with moat and all that, ROIC is strong and I have a bargain price, I could estimate that its normalize ROIC is around 25% average for 3 years in the next 3 years. Actually after apply dcf, it seems that intrinsic value is really not that great, but I’m placing a lot of my trust and business still have room to grow at this cheap price and I’m not gonna be very conservative I’m assuming a lot of growth room and if they can maintain that strong</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I bought a premium stock data tool today, will use it and my first stock analysis in a while is once again SGN equipped with my new valuation knowledge. So even with moat and all that, ROIC is strong and I have a bargain price, I could estimate that its normalize ROIC is around 25% average for 3 years in the next 3 years. Actually after apply dcf, it seems that intrinsic value is really not that great, but I’m placing a lot of my trust and business still have room to grow at this cheap price and I’m not gonna be very conservative I’m assuming a lot of growth room and if they can maintain that strong]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Learning Jul 15</title><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jul-15/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning Jul 15"/><published>2025-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jul-15</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jul-15/"><![CDATA[<p>I read through some of the Greenblatt lecture and valuation and I’m most of the time confused, which is a good sign that there’s more thing to learn about and I’m not at the end of the road in term of picking stocks. He talks about valuation but I still don’t quite get all of what he’s saying as well as his case studies. He also involves a lot scuttlebutting which I don’t know how to get start. But just number crunching and small business I guess is enough for reasonably well investing. Greenblatt is definitely a Buffett type of investor where he focus on compounding and good business that can grow compared to typical roadkill stock like me and Michael Burry operate. I mean road kill stock are easy and I’ve found relative success in them like FCM, however, I can’t hold them for too long or find a multi bagger and I could expand on my skills to find these companies that can grow 10 times in 10 years. All of the company that is the top of his criteria all are multi baggers over the years and I can use this to further analyze. Also what’s my competence and business that I can understand, oil business definitely not, consumer and retail have a bunch of tricky inventory and stuff like that so no, technology I’m in it, but Vietnam are all outsourced projects so no point in there so now I’m literally relied on metrics and general business knowledge.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I read through some of the Greenblatt lecture and valuation and I’m most of the time confused, which is a good sign that there’s more thing to learn about and I’m not at the end of the road in term of picking stocks. He talks about valuation but I still don’t quite get all of what he’s saying as well as his case studies. He also involves a lot scuttlebutting which I don’t know how to get start. But just number crunching and small business I guess is enough for reasonably well investing. Greenblatt is definitely a Buffett type of investor where he focus on compounding and good business that can grow compared to typical roadkill stock like me and Michael Burry operate. I mean road kill stock are easy and I’ve found relative success in them like FCM, however, I can’t hold them for too long or find a multi bagger and I could expand on my skills to find these companies that can grow 10 times in 10 years. All of the company that is the top of his criteria all are multi baggers over the years and I can use this to further analyze. Also what’s my competence and business that I can understand, oil business definitely not, consumer and retail have a bunch of tricky inventory and stuff like that so no, technology I’m in it, but Vietnam are all outsourced projects so no point in there so now I’m literally relied on metrics and general business knowledge.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Learning Jul 14</title><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jul-14/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning Jul 14"/><published>2025-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jul-14</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jul-14/"><![CDATA[<ul> <li>So my calculation is wrong, Vietnam finally manage to lock in a trade deal with the US and only a 20%, so I missed a lot of money made and this is a mistake on my part to give up my positions so easily. Although I could be right and stocks drop, I could use the previous position and add more to my position, and trim off a little bit rather than half. This again is a lesson that I should never give up my position so easily if all of my value are not realized. As Buffett says, I’d rather a bumpy 15% rather than a smooth 12%</li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So my calculation is wrong, Vietnam finally manage to lock in a trade deal with the US and only a 20%, so I missed a lot of money made and this is a mistake on my part to give up my positions so easily. Although I could be right and stocks drop, I could use the previous position and add more to my position, and trim off a little bit rather than half. This again is a lesson that I should never give up my position so easily if all of my value are not realized. As Buffett says, I’d rather a bumpy 15% rather than a smooth 12%]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Learning Jul 13</title><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jul-13/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning Jul 13"/><published>2025-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jul-13</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jul-13/"><![CDATA[<p>The market rises higher and higher and it looks like we enter a craze period and now should I lock in my profits. No not right</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The market rises higher and higher and it looks like we enter a craze period and now should I lock in my profits. No not right]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Learning Jul 11</title><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jul-11/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning Jul 11"/><published>2025-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jul-11</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jul-11/"><![CDATA[<p>The market has risen approximately 16% year to date, and I did not fully capitalize on it because I already half every single position since my tariff judgement is that I could lose 10 to 20% and could probably make around 5 - 10% if the market move right. Turns out it’s around 15%. I thought I should’ve thought about it more carefully, but anyway, I’m wrong and I miss the opportunity to make some more money, but also I preserve a lot of money rather than lose it permanent, so even though I did not make more, I did not lose it. But is there any chance I could have revised my decision and bought more? I guess not, the moment I sell, it’s impossible to buy back unless there is a huge thing happen, so I guess I should not give my position so easily? Even if I revise my thesis, it’s impossible to buy back anyway.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The market has risen approximately 16% year to date, and I did not fully capitalize on it because I already half every single position since my tariff judgement is that I could lose 10 to 20% and could probably make around 5 - 10% if the market move right. Turns out it’s around 15%. I thought I should’ve thought about it more carefully, but anyway, I’m wrong and I miss the opportunity to make some more money, but also I preserve a lot of money rather than lose it permanent, so even though I did not make more, I did not lose it. But is there any chance I could have revised my decision and bought more? I guess not, the moment I sell, it’s impossible to buy back unless there is a huge thing happen, so I guess I should not give my position so easily? Even if I revise my thesis, it’s impossible to buy back anyway.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Learning Jul 10</title><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jul-10/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning Jul 10"/><published>2025-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jul-10</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jul-10/"><![CDATA[<p>Read through Greenblatt and he is the modern type of Graham that instead of focusing on net net (company that trades below liquidation value). As Greenblatt says, it’s very rare nowadays and instead he suggest another formula which focus on high ROIC (return on capital, low investment, high return basically), and we can get them for cheap (low P/E rate). I don’t know what’s the margin of safety for this even though he mentioned margin of safety a lot. But I have compiled a list that fits on to his criteria and here are the best <a href="evernote:///view/246850237/s432/c8bb8aae-bcb6-6699-9da5-079705cd8b5b#a7759ecc-0753-4b10-ab81-3e9e3eb47d4c/775bbfcb-d458-491f-ac8e-da9bcb6afb69">stocks</a>. Here’s the top 30 NTL, DSN, SMB, VFG, BFC, SGN, LAF, ADP, BCE, SJD, SCS, UIC, HTG, VNL, TDC, TCL, ABT, RAL, NVT, NCT, NSC, VTO, DVP, LIX, VAF, GDT, BMP, TRC, TTE, FMC, NNC</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Read through Greenblatt and he is the modern type of Graham that instead of focusing on net net (company that trades below liquidation value). As Greenblatt says, it’s very rare nowadays and instead he suggest another formula which focus on high ROIC (return on capital, low investment, high return basically), and we can get them for cheap (low P/E rate). I don’t know what’s the margin of safety for this even though he mentioned margin of safety a lot. But I have compiled a list that fits on to his criteria and here are the best stocks. Here’s the top 30 NTL, DSN, SMB, VFG, BFC, SGN, LAF, ADP, BCE, SJD, SCS, UIC, HTG, VNL, TDC, TCL, ABT, RAL, NVT, NCT, NSC, VTO, DVP, LIX, VAF, GDT, BMP, TRC, TTE, FMC, NNC]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Learning Jun 24</title><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jun-24/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning Jun 24"/><published>2025-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jun-24</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jun-24/"><![CDATA[<ul> <li>News came out that the fish product that a company I’m tracking that is exporting Striped catfish may be able to suffer no tariff, but there is no name from the company I’m targeting. I wasn’t able to get a good price for it because it’s been trading so thinly, but I will buying in today as well since the liquidation value is around 10k, which is basically 2/3 of the price.</li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[News came out that the fish product that a company I’m tracking that is exporting Striped catfish may be able to suffer no tariff, but there is no name from the company I’m targeting. I wasn’t able to get a good price for it because it’s been trading so thinly, but I will buying in today as well since the liquidation value is around 10k, which is basically 2/3 of the price.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Learning Jun 23</title><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jun-23/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning Jun 23"/><published>2025-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jun-23</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jun-23/"><![CDATA[<ul> <li>A lot of political stuff happens in the past few days but still there’re some interesting things to look at</li> <li>A potential M&amp;A gonna happen is that Thien Long Group (company that provide stationery and such) will be acquiring Phuong Nam corp, a bookstore chain. Both of these guys are well known players and this could be a play for me to look in to lock in some profit, as Buffett says, when the market level is expensive, it’s better to have these M&amp;A stocks. <ul> <li>So upon reviewing TLG is a really strong compounding business that manage to 10x its size over the last 10 years and its cheap relative to its earnings. However, it’s an established enterprise now and it seems that it’s struggling to grow more. Still, not enough conviction and not cheap enough for me to buy this. Following this merger though, TLG maybe undervalued with relative to its price in the long term for me to hold. However, I feel that it’s not cheap enough and I still don’t have enough conviction to make a long term call that worth the price. This is still speculating and needs a lot of things to go right in order to make a profit, unlike in distressed and cheap company that just 1 thing going right will tip the balance</li> </ul> </li> <li>Read through some news and Musk’s new robotaxi caught my eye. It definitely cause a huge jump in Tesla stock. I read through an article by Ark Investment (a pretty infamous firm that focuses on disrupting technology and place insane valuation for disruptive stocks), put Tesla to be worth 5 times it currently worth in the next 4 years. Pretty insane, but they make the right early call in Tesla and Palantir so they’re might be right.</li> <li>Today, I also see that Michael Burry has sold all of his positions, which a large positions in Chinese stocks, and holding put options (essentially shorting) NVIDIA and Chinese Stocks. So he’s in my camp as well to sell off a lot of his positions and be reserve. I’ve missed a huge rise of STB compared to a concentrated portfolio but it’s whatever, I still keep the profit from holding it</li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A lot of political stuff happens in the past few days but still there’re some interesting things to look at A potential M&amp;A gonna happen is that Thien Long Group (company that provide stationery and such) will be acquiring Phuong Nam corp, a bookstore chain. Both of these guys are well known players and this could be a play for me to look in to lock in some profit, as Buffett says, when the market level is expensive, it’s better to have these M&amp;A stocks. So upon reviewing TLG is a really strong compounding business that manage to 10x its size over the last 10 years and its cheap relative to its earnings. However, it’s an established enterprise now and it seems that it’s struggling to grow more. Still, not enough conviction and not cheap enough for me to buy this. Following this merger though, TLG maybe undervalued with relative to its price in the long term for me to hold. However, I feel that it’s not cheap enough and I still don’t have enough conviction to make a long term call that worth the price. This is still speculating and needs a lot of things to go right in order to make a profit, unlike in distressed and cheap company that just 1 thing going right will tip the balance Read through some news and Musk’s new robotaxi caught my eye. It definitely cause a huge jump in Tesla stock. I read through an article by Ark Investment (a pretty infamous firm that focuses on disrupting technology and place insane valuation for disruptive stocks), put Tesla to be worth 5 times it currently worth in the next 4 years. Pretty insane, but they make the right early call in Tesla and Palantir so they’re might be right. Today, I also see that Michael Burry has sold all of his positions, which a large positions in Chinese stocks, and holding put options (essentially shorting) NVIDIA and Chinese Stocks. So he’s in my camp as well to sell off a lot of his positions and be reserve. I’ve missed a huge rise of STB compared to a concentrated portfolio but it’s whatever, I still keep the profit from holding it]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Learning-Jun-13</title><link href="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jun-13/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning-Jun-13"/><published>2025-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jun-13</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alshedivat.github.io/al-folio/blog/2025/learning-jun-13/"><![CDATA[<ul> <li>Sass business, then and now. In the past, software business is more geared towards one time fee (i.e $500 for a microsoft office), now however, most software is on a subscription model, which is much more sustainable as well as stable revenue (i.e Google Docs). LTV of each software is 1 / Churn rate, Customer Acquistion Cost is the cost in order to spent on each customer (i.e marketing, benefits, cost of capital), if a Sass business have this ratio is less than 1, then it’s a bad business. Good companies like Amazon or Spotify will have a huge LTV and CAC. <ul> <li>Net New MRR: the incremental dollars add to install base each month. Basically how much the business is growing. These incremental dollar formula is something similar to: New MRR (New Customers) + Upgrade MRR (Existing Customers) - Downgrade MRR (Existing Customer downgrade product) - Cancellation MRR (Lost Custoemrs). This need to be continualy positive for the company to grow. However, MRR is an internal tool and it’s not a really public number. **</li> </ul> </li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sass business, then and now. In the past, software business is more geared towards one time fee (i.e $500 for a microsoft office), now however, most software is on a subscription model, which is much more sustainable as well as stable revenue (i.e Google Docs). LTV of each software is 1 / Churn rate, Customer Acquistion Cost is the cost in order to spent on each customer (i.e marketing, benefits, cost of capital), if a Sass business have this ratio is less than 1, then it’s a bad business. Good companies like Amazon or Spotify will have a huge LTV and CAC. Net New MRR: the incremental dollars add to install base each month. Basically how much the business is growing. These incremental dollar formula is something similar to: New MRR (New Customers) + Upgrade MRR (Existing Customers) - Downgrade MRR (Existing Customer downgrade product) - Cancellation MRR (Lost Custoemrs). This need to be continualy positive for the company to grow. However, MRR is an internal tool and it’s not a really public number. **]]></summary></entry></feed>